Gabrielle Jacobs

Front End Web Developer

• Dallas, TX, 75287

☑ GMJacobsDev@gmail.com

469-626-7843

★ GMJacobsDev.com

in Linkedin.com/in/gabrielle-jacobs

Github.com/GabbyJ



PROFILE

Passionate front-end web developer with 4+ years of experience designing, developing, and managing responsive websites in the digital media industry with a multimedia background. Proficient in HTML, CSS, Javascript; plus modern libraries and frameworks. Seeking an opportunity to contribute web development and multimedia skills in an environment that encourages learning and growth.

EXPERIENCE

React Developer 10/2020 – 12/2020

The Collab Lab

Remote

- Working on a team of early-career developers under the guidance of experienced professionals
- Using Agile processes to build a production progressive web app (PWA) using React and Firebase over the course of 8 weeks
- Emphasizes pair programming, peer reviewing, and participating in weekly demos and retros

Digital Content and Wordpress Lead

Wieck ☑

- 11/2019 present Richardson, TX
- Fix bugs and add website features to production 80% quicker than average by streamlining the ticketing process
- Improve the design and function of custom pages by adding CSS/ JS customizations
- Achieve a 1-on-1 line of communication for all 6 Wordpress clients to provide assistance, updates, and maintenance 50% faster
- Create custom templates from stage to production 60% quicker by both streamlining the ticketing process and providing unique customization knowledge
- Continue Content Management Specialist duties

Digital Content Management Specialist

Wieck ☑

- 1 of 4 employees responsible for updating 15+ websites with releases, social media, images, videos, and graphics
- Provide internal and external support with an average 30 min turn around for multiple major car, health, and news corporations, an airline, and others
- Inform thousands of people on important corporate news within 30 mins through custom email blasts for 10+ countries/divisions

06/2017 – 11/2019 Richardson, TX

Customer Service

Amusement Park/Retail

05/2015 – 11/2016 Pittsburgh, PA/Dallas, TX

Media InternShoutside Media
Pittsburgh, PA

- Built and maintained 3 Wordpress sites for lawyers and doctors
- Responsible for recording professional quality commercials and stock footage for 5 local companies
- Improved video editing techniques using Adobe Premiere and After Effects

SKILLS

Languages (HTML, CSS, Javascript (ES6), Python)

Frameworks/Libraries (SCSS (Sass), Bootstrap, jQuery, React, Node, Express)

Dev Tools (Visual Studio Code, Git, Github, NPM, Wordpress, Netlify)

Design Tools (Photoshop, Adobe XD, CodePen, Canva)

Miscellaneous (Responsive Design, Accessibility, Jira, Google Analytics, Agile, Microsoft Office)

Soft Skills (Problem Solving, Creativity, Willingness to learn, Self Starter, Dependable, Communication, Teamwork)

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science (B.S.) in Graphic Communications & Multimedia

California University of Pennsylvania

• 3.3 GPA

08/2012 – 12/2015 California, PA

CERTIFICATES

Responsive Web Design

FreeCodeCamp - Proven knowledge of HTML5, CSS3, Responsiveness, and Accessibility - Completed: 2019

MERN Full Stack Web Development

Udemy – Focuses on React, Node, Express, MongoDB. Also covers Bootstrap, Javascript, jQuery, EJS, SQL, Authentication – In Progress...

COMMUNITY CONTRIBUTIONS

Hacktoberfest 10/2020

Open Source Contributor

FreeCodeCamp Dallas 09/2018 - 03/2020

Mentor, Participant Dallas, TX

 Work with Dallas students to complete the responsive Web Design Certificate on FreeCodeCamp and assist them with code-alongs at meet ups